What's going on, Jonathan?
>> I'm going on. How you doing?
>> Good. Welcome to Cincinnati.
>> Thank you so much. I appreciate it.
>> What's the uh last couple days been like
for you?
>> Yeah, it's it's been good. Um been
talking to Cincinnati for a while and uh
you know, just glad to make it official.
I'm super excited to be here. It's a
great opportunity, you know, for the
team and for me and my family
personally. So, honestly, I'm just
looking forward to getting started and
getting to work.
What was it about the fit here that
attracted you? Uh,
>> you know, I think there was multiple
things. I think, you know, as a
defensive lineman, having the ability to
play with a guy like Joe Burrow and that
offense, allowing, you know, you know,
they're going to put points up, you
know, we're going to be playing with the
lead. So, allowing us as a defense and
defensive line to kind of get after the
quarterback was definitely enticing. And
just the defensive staff that we've had
here. Um, Coach Montgomery, I've known
him for 15 years. I mean, he recruited
me out of high school. So just just
between, you know, Burrow and the
offense and the defensive staff here, I
thought it was just honestly the best
fit for me.
>> Do you and Jerry stay close that whole
time?
>> Yes, sir. Yeah, he coached me at the Pro
Bowl. Um I mean, obviously he was in
Green Bay for a while, so after every
game, me and him would always connect
like that. So definitely a guy that I'm
fond I think fondly of.
>> Any players on this roster that you're
>> not not too much. I'm kind of a loner
when it comes to the league. Kind of,
you know, just a family guy, stay in my
own lane, but I'm sure I'm going to get
to know everybody, you know, very soon.
We know you as both a run stuffer and a
pass rusher. What do you think is the
best part of your game?
>> Um, it's funny. Um, Gino Atkins is
always a guy that I've liked to look at
just cuz he's not the biggest guy. And,
uh, I think for me it's the ability to
play all three downs. Um, that's
something that I've always prided myself
on is be able to stop the run on first
and second down and affect the
quarterback on third down. So, for me, I
would just say the ability to play all
phases of the game.
John, what uh um you know, you played a
lot of snaps last year.
[clears throat and cough] Is that I
mean, obviously, do you think you might
be more effective? Jerry, you know,
Jerry kind of handled you a certain way.
You don't have to play 800.
>> Yeah. You know, the tough part is
there's always a fine balance of not
playing too much, but also getting
enough. And you know, for me, I've
always struggled with that cuz obviously
I want to play as much as I can. Um, so
that's something that we definitely
talked about finding that perfect
balance between
65 to 75% whatever the percentage may
be. But I definitely think that's
important to you know being able to stay
fresh for that throughout the you know
course of the season.
>> Anything in particular about Gino? I
don't know if you ever did you ever
watch Gino tape or anything or uh you
know down through the years? I mean you
were still in the league when he was in
the league. So
>> yeah I mean I mean the thing that jumps
off Amelia is his explosiveness. I mean,
just I mean, just his ability to just
completely just take over games from the
inside. I mean, in the run game and the
pass game. So, he's definitely a guy
that I've not only just tried to model
my game after, but but looked at his
tape as something that's repeatable, you
know what I mean? Cuz he he did it
without being 6'5, 350, you know what I
mean? A size that uh a size that you
can't do unless you're that size, you
know? So, he's definitely one of my
favorite guys to watch. Did you I mean
with him they talked about his speed,
but I guess it was as much technique as
anything.
>> I would say more technique than speed. I
think the speed is what wowed the fans,
but when you really break down his film,
I mean he he was such a technical run
stopper and pass rusher. You know what I
mean?
>> A lot of times it's the guys on the edge
who get to the quarterback who get all
the attention. As someone who's played
in this league for a long time, how
valuable is inside pass rush? Well, you
know, something that I always believe is
sacks are situational. Um, some of my
best games of my career, I've had no
sacks. And some of the games where I
don't really feel like I played too
well, I ended up with two sacks. And
it's not just about guys winning
one-on-one. It's about all four of us
rushing together. You know, I could beat
my guard off the snap every single play,
but if our left end doesn't keep
containing the quarterback gets out,
I'll never get to him. So, I I I think
it's super important as interior guys,
we don't create a space for the
quarterback to step up. And as the edge,
you got to bend that corner and make the
quarterback step up. And at that point,
it kind of up to the quarterback to
decide who gets a sack. Um, you know, so
for me, my mindset is just going in to
make sure I collapse the pocket at all
costs and just try to make the
quarterback as uncomfortable as
possible.
>> With knowing Jerry for as long as you
have, um, he's still relatively new to
Cincinnati. What can you say just from
your point of view on his coaching style
and what you sort of hope to uh to
achieve with him in your time here?
Yeah, I mean he's definitely a
nononsense guy who wears his heart on
his sleeve and I think as a defensive
line, we're in nature emotional players,
emotional creatures. So, I mean, when
you look at the guys he's coached from
Kenny Clark, you know, um he's coached a
lot of, you know, big time players and
he's gotten a lot of production out of
him. So, I'm excited, you know, for the
first time to be able to, you know, play
under him and hopefully he can help grow
my game in any way possible and, you
know, we can uh achieve some great
things here. your when you look at your
your games played, I'm I'm sure you
played through stuff, but you've never
hardly missed games at all and then the
the pec a couple years ago. Was that or
was it oblique?
>> Oh, it was a pec. Yes.
>> Yeah. Um when that happened, were they
saying it could be season ending or was
there always that hope that you because
you came back and play?
>> So, so at first it was season ending,
but then when they went in, they seen
some scar tissuing which indicated that
it was kind of a older injury that just
kind of went at that time. So, they kind
of told me when I woke up that there was
a chance I was going to be able to come
back. And once they told me that, I
mean, that was just the goal, just 10
weeks, get under that bench, start
building it back up, and get ready for
the playoffs.
>> What was that like? Cuz I know that's
what you guys play for, to chase a ring,
and you hadn't really had a what, one
playoff game before that season. Get a
taste of that.
>> It was unreal. It was unreal. Um, I
mean, there's there's nothing like it.
Um, playing playoff football is is
unreal. And I mean, Cincinnati's not too
far removed from the Super Bowl. So, I
mean, with a guy like Joe Bro and that
offense and, you know, things we're
going to be able to do on defense, you
know, it's going to be an exciting year
and looking forward to see what we can
do.
>> When you look at the current D line that
the Bengals have from this past season,
is there anything that sort of has stuck
out to you or have you seen any sort of
tape? I know you guys played them last
year once. Um,
>> yeah, very very young defensive line,
which can be a good and a bad thing.
obviously inexperienced sometimes things
happen, but very young, athletic,
aggressive defensive line and I think
I'm going to be able to fit in well with
them and, you know, I'm going to do
everything in my power to help elevate
their game as they're going to be able
to ele elevate my game. Um, yeah, it's
just going to be really exciting and
fun. So, I can't wait to get to meet the
guys and, you know, get this work
started.
>> When you get to year 10 like you're
going to be and you start looking for
the perfect fit, is it winning? Is it
opportunity? What what do you put your
values as the most important part of
where you want to sign?
>> For me, it was where where I thought I
was going to be the most happy, you know
what I mean? Um, and I never thought I
was it was always winning, but for me,
it was I want to go somewhere that we
have a chance to compete and where I
feel like I can showcase my talents and
help, you know, help the team at the
same time. And this is one of the few
places where I felt like I could have my
cake and eat it, too. I mean, again,
when you have a guy like Burrow, you
always have a chance. You're never out
of it. And you know, with with the
coaches we have here and the players
that they already have in and they've
been bringing in, I just felt like this
was the perfect fit for me and my
family.
>> You you mentioned Burrow a couple times.
You were on a hit with the ACL on
sometimes when that happens, a bond, a
friendship forms. Have Have you did you
speak with him after that? Have you got
Have you stayed in contact with him
after that?
>> Honestly, no. Like I said, I'm I'm kind
of a loner. Kind of do my own thing. Um,
obviously he was able to come back
stronger than ever and go to the Super
Bowl the next year. So, um, I'm looking
forward to get get a chance to
officially meet him. Yeah.
>> You get I guess you got a sense of the
environment the game a couple years ago.
I think it was a couple years ago with
when him and Jay lit it up.
>> Yeah, that was that was a fun game to be
an offensive guy. Um, I was telling my
wife that um that environment was insane
Monday night. Um, and it's funny because
after we got back Washington, we kind of
copied some of the things that you guys
were doing here from the just the from
turning off the lights and everyone
having their flashlight out and just
little things like that. So, I'm looking
forward to this environment for sure.
>> Good.
>> Great.
>> Appreciate you guys.